

Domenico Camasta

☑ domenicocamasta@gmail.com 📞 3701522690 🔮 Via F. Baracca 8, Bologna (Italy) 🛗 29/12/1983

► Italian 👗 He/Him 🖈 portfolio.devcrumbs.com 🔘 d-cmst

Profile

I'm a mathematician by education and self-taught software developer for passion, with over 10 years of experience building full-stack web applications with Python, JavaScript, React, Node.js and PHP. My expertise also includes systems administration and databases management/optimization.

I'm currently trying to rebase in Bologna after some years abroad, looking for job opportunities in/near the city.

Professional Experience

Developer, *UserTesting* □

2018 - 12/2022

Creating and executing usability tests to evaluate the ease of use, efficiency, and overall user experience of software products: designing test plans, coding test scripts, recruiting test participants, and analyzing test results.

UK | Germany | Remote

Developer, Appen Ltd Chatbot software development. 2020 - 2022

Remote

Project Manager, *UniD Formazione* □

2015 - 2018

Development, deployment and system administration for the company web applications.

Borgo Maggiore, RSM

Teacher, MIUR □

2011 - 2014

Mathematics/Logic teacher for high school and university students.

Verona, Italy

Languages

Italian Native

English

TOEFL 2020

Education

PhD, Università "La Sapienza"

2007 - 2010

PhD Program in Mathematical Logic | Thesis title: "A two-dimensional semantics for natural language formalization"

Rome, Italy

Master Degree, Università Degli Studi di Genova Italian Master Degree (Laurea Magistrale) – Mathematics

2002 - 2007 Genova, Italy

Certificates

TOEFL

PCAP - Certified Associate in Python Programming

Test date: 2020

Year: 2019

Score: 98/120 (Advanced)

Score: 92%

Projects

AGReATWine, Contributor □

2020 - present

Creation of a database of Italian wines included in DOCG appellations, evaluated by the three main national wine guides

KDE, Contributor, Member □

2005 - present

Code, designs and translations for many desktop applications and web applications from the KDE ecosystem.

ArchLinux, *Package mantainer* ☑

2005 - present

Arch Linux is a Linux distribution that tries to Keep It Simple

WireGuard, Contributor ☑

2020 - 2022

WireGuard is an extremely simple yet fast and modern VPN

GSConnect, Contributor □

Complete implementation of KDE Connect especially for GNOME Shell.

InvoicePlane, *Contributor* □

A self-hosted open source application for managing your invoices, clients and payments.

RAMP, Contributor

Ramp is a python library for rapid prototyping of machine learning solutions. It's a light-weight pandas-based machine learning framework pluggable with existing python machine learning and statistics tools.

Wiki.js, *Patch contributor* □

Wiki.js is a modern and powerful wiki app built on Node.js

Publications

Collana UnidTest, Libri per la preparazione dei test di ammissione universitari 🛚

Other certificates

Italian Sommelier Association - Diploma 🗷

01/2020

Diploma di Sommelier rilasciato dall'Associazione Italiana Sommelier

Bologna, Italy